B.MITHUN RAJ

Email: mithunlb@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 9566450484



OBJECTIVE

Accountant with BCom., MBA(FM) degree, 6+ years related work experience and a strong background in Finance and Accounting methodologies and practices. and to be start the professional in **SAP FICO** Position in a reputed organization when I can use all my knowledge and experience in a benefit the organization

KEY SKLLS

General Ledger Cash accounting Accounts Receivable/Payable
Financial Accounting Bank Reconciliations
Petty cash management Time Management Online Bank Transactions

CAPABILITIES

- ❖ Well developed analytical skills Skillful at processing data/information, keeping records and tabulation.
- ❖ Strong background in bookkeeping includes General Ledger, Accounts payable/ receivable, Final Accounts and reporting.
- ❖ Interact professionally with all levels of staff and maintain the highest level of confidentiality; known for tact and diplomacy in handling sensitive issues.
- **Effective** communication skills, excellent Tamil, Malayalam & English, especially written, combined with interpersonal strengths and a high degree of professional integrity.
- ❖ Computer skills: SAP FICO, Tally (ERP 9), Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Internet browsing & Email.

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Branch Accountant (SAP FICO) – VLCC HEALTH CARE LTD(Chennai) Aug 2017 to present

- ❖ Monitor and maintain the accounts for daily sales cash transactions, amounting
- Maintain Journal, General ledger handling and all books of accounts up to Final accounts & Balance sheet.
- * Closing mandatorily monthly financial Statement.
- Monthly MIS Report Analyzing
- ❖ Manage the Bank Reconciliation Statements of the Company for all receipts and payments.
- ❖ Verification of data and Maintenance of Outstanding reports for debtors and creditors.
- ❖ Generate and Maintain of sales inventory report.

❖ Generate accounts reports pertaining to GST,SGST/IGST and TDS.

Accountant – HERCULES GROUPS ,ATTINGAL(TRIVENDURAM) April 2016 to Mar 2017

- General Accounting, Prepare Journal, ledger
- Create Sales invoice, debit, credit note
- Verification of debtors and creditors.
- ❖ Bank Reconciliation daily and monthly as required
- Inventory management
- ❖ Generate accounts reports pertaining & VAT/CST and TDS Filling
- Payroll management Maintaining

Accountant & Office Administrator- CHRIST CMI CENTRAL SCHOOL, NAGERCOIL Jan 2015 to Mar 2016

- Working with spreadsheets, General ledger and journals.
- Managing payables & Receivables Transaction.
- Calculating and checking to make sure payments, amounts and records are correct.
- Managing petty cash transactions.
- Reconciling finance accounts and direct debits.
- ❖ Generate Salary statements and run Payroll Management
- * Responsible for bank reconciliation statements every month.

Office Assistant & Computer operator- ESL (Cent.govt Contract Basic) Aug 2013 to 2014 Dec

- * Receive all incoming correspondence and packages and route to correct recipient.
- Assist with payroll and employee scheduling.
- Full office maintenance work
- Store Maintanance

Accounts assistant- Faurecia Emmissions Control Tech pvt ltd Nov 2011 to Jun 2013

- Prepare Journal, Ledger Entries
- Sales Dispatch Work
- Prepare Vendor and supplier invoices
- ❖ Banking Reconciliation work
- Making Cheque & Filling Maintanance work

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

- * Bachelor of Commerce, Pioneer Kumaraswamy College, Nagercoil 2008-2011
- MBA Finance Management, University of Madrash, Chennai- 2012-2014

Strengths

- MS Excel
- Time Management
- Team Leadership
- Flexibility
- Accuracy

Languages Known

- English
- **♦** Tamil
- Malayalam

Certifications

- **❖** SAP FICO
- **❖** Tally ERP
- ♦ Mfg Pro ERP
- MS-Office

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name - MITHUN RAJ B
BIO : 12/04/1990
NATIONALITY : INDIAN
GENDER : MALE
MARITAL STATUS : SINGLE
PASSPORT DETAILS : K9983647
NOTICE PERIOD : 30 DAYS

CONTACT DETAILS

235 VEERVILAI COLONY, THITTUVILAI BHOOTHAPANDY(PO) KANYAKUMARI DISTRICT

PIN-629852

With Best

Regards

MITHUN RAJ B